A Guide to the Rufus Wilmot Griswold Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7104-b
Rufus Wilmot Griswold Collection 1838-1854
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7104-b
16 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 1963 December 17 ] 1967 June 27
Item Listing
- Letters
  - William Slade to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1838 July 28; ALS, 2 p.
    [Requests publication of excerpts from the
    Emancipator
    and his correspondence with students of Bangor Theological Seminary which had appeared in the
    Evangelist
    . ]
  - [John Lewis] O'Sullivan to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1841 July 5; ALS, 1 p.
    [Accompanying the corrected copy of a report. Offers to write a preface to it. Sends respects to Mr. [Richard Henry] Dana and inquires about the cost of 10,000 copies of the report.]
  - Thomas Colley Grattan to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1843 January 16; ALS, 2 p.
    [Comments on a melancholy letter received from Rufus Wilmot Griswold and negotiates the sale of two tales to
    Graham's Magazine
  - Thomas Colley Grattan to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1843 November 27; ALS, 3 p.
    [Acknowledges receipt of three copies of his short story and expresses concern over its having been published in an unauthorized form. Also asks about the payment he will receive for it.]
  - Hiram Ketcham to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1844 April 1; ALS, 1 p.
    [Regrets he cannot comply with the request for an article on Romanism because of other commitments.]
  - Thomas Bangs Thorpe to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1845 May 15; ALS, 1 p.
    [Accompanying a biographical sketch. Expresses appreciation for Griswold's contributions to American literature. Suggests that the first great original national writing will come from the south.]
  - [ Thomas Dow Jones] to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, [1846] February 24; ALS, 1 p.
    [Requests that Griswold call briefly to see his sculpture.]
  - L. R. [Koecker] to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1850 November 1; ALS, 1p.
    [Concerns his recent trip to Europe, the publication of the
    Life of Poe
    and the
    Life of Paul Jones
    . Requests letters of Washington Irving, George Payne Rainsford, or other "worthies."]
  - Lewis Cass to Rufus Wilmot Griswold(Body of letter in hand of clerk), 1851 December 15; LS, 2 p.
    [Regrets his inability to participate in planning a memorial to James Fenimore Cooper and expresses his admiration of Cooper's work.]
  - H. F. Phinney to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1852 July 17; ALS, 2 p.
    [Announces gift of Cooper's
    History of the Navy
    to Rufus Wilmot Griswold and requests any letters regarding Mr. Cooper addressed to Mr. [Washington] Irving or Rufus Wilmot Griswold be sent to him.]
  - Charles Augustus Stetson to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1853 January 13; ALS, 2 p.
    [Asks that he call to discuss with Mr. [Horatio] Greenough the intentions of the Bostonians regarding publication of "
    The Memorial
    . "]
  - Henry Charles Carey to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1853 May 14; ALS, 2 p.
    [Concerns an accident in which Rufus Wilmot Griswold's daughter was injured. Mentions his book which he hoped Rufus Wilmot Griswold would "give notice of."]
  - Henry Charles Carey to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1853 September 29; ALS, 2 p.
    [Indicates his desire to visit Rufus Wilmot Griswold while in New York. ]
  - John Jay Smith to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1854 December 11; ALS, 1 p.
    [Expresses appreciation of
    The Republican Court
    in which several ancestors ( James Logan, a Morris, a Neill, Thomas Lloyd, the Moores) are mentioned. Indicates a volume on the Neill family is being sent to Rufus Wilmot Griswold]
  - [John Lewis] O'Sullivan to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, n.d.; ALS, 3 p.
    [Inquires about a story submitted for publication, and rates paid various authors such as [Nathaniel Parker] Willis and [Caroline Matilda] Kirkland. Also asks when
    Rev. Ballads and Anecdotes of the American Bar
    will be sent.]